Guide to the Oskar Morgenstern Papers, 1866-1992 and undated RL.10033
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Subject Files Series, 1893-1987 and undated
  - The Green Revolution, from Taste of America by John L. and Karen Hess, 1977 (Box 43)
  - Grenzen der Wirtschaftspolitik, 1952 (Box 43)
  - Grenznutzen Theorie: Systematische (Systematic Theory of Marginal Utility), 1927-1931, undated (Box 43)
  - Gross National Product and Accuracy of Statistics, 1955-1976, undated, 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Gross National Product, 1963-1975, undated (Box 43)
  - Growth and Decay, 1963-1975, undated, 2 folders (Box 44)
  - Guilbaud, G. Th.: Game Theory, 1952-1954 (Box 44)
  - Hagen, Ole, Towards a Positive Theory of Preferences under Risk, 1976 (Box 44)
  - Hamilton College Lecture, 1969 (Box 95)
  - Harvard-Leontief Project I, 1938, 1948-1950, undated (Box 95)
  - Harvard-Leontief Project II, 1948-1950, undated (Box 95)
  - Hayek, Friedrich August von, 1977 (Box 44)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1977 (Box 44)
  - Heiss, Klaus P., 1973 (Box 44)
  - Herzfeld, Ernst, 1947-1951, undated (Box 44)
  - Hester, James M., Social Reponsibility of Organizations in a Free Society, 1974: 1973-1975 (Box 44)
  - History of Economic Theory: Bernoulli, Gossen, Menger, etc., 1964-1976, undated (Box 44)
  - History of Economic Theory: Cameralists and Mercantilists, 1964-1976, undated (Box 44)
  - History of Economic Theory: Cournot and Dupuit, 1966-1975, undated (Box 45)
  - History of Economic Theory: Physiocrats and Cantillon, 1962-1967, undated (Box 45)
  - History of Economic Theory: Ricardo, 1964-1976, undated (Box 45)
  - History of Economic Theory: J. H. von Thuenen, 1959-1964, undated (Box 45)
  - Hochschild, Mary Marquand: Memorial, 1974 (Box 45)
  - Horowitz, Ira, 1973-1974 (Box 45)
  - IAS/Navy National Aviation Meeting, 1961 (Box 95)
  - IBM Symposium, 1964-1965 (Box 95)
  - IBM Symposium-Washington D.C., 1968 (Box 95)
  - Incoming Inquiries, Job Seekers, Applicants, 1954-1958 (Box 95)
  - Indifference Curves, 1938-1970, undated (Box 45)
  - Inequality, 1945-1969, undated (Box 45)
  - Inflation, 1973 (Box 45)
  - Input-Ouput Tables- Japan, undated (Box 95)
  - Input-Output: Other Organizations Engineering Research Associates, 1953 (Box 95)
  - Institut de Fance: Academie des Sciences Morales et Politiques, 1968-1969 (Box 95)
  - Institut de la Vie, 1969-1977, undated, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Institute for Advanced Studies, 1963-1965 (Box 95)
  - Institute for Advanced Studies, 1967-1972 (Box 95)
  - Institute for Advanced Studies, Vienna, 1963-1967, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Institute for Advanced Studies, Vienna, 1970-1977, undated, 3 folders (Box 46)
  - Institute for Advanced Study: Monetary Policy Seminars, 1945-1947 (Box 46)
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1964-1967 (Box 95)
  - International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis, 1974-1975, undated (Box 46)
  - International Mathematical Congress- Moscow, 1966 (Box 95)
  - Internatinal Symposium Vienna (Carl Menger), 1969-1970 (Box 95)
  - International Statistical Institute, 1945-1953, undated (Box 46)
  - International Workshop on Basic Problems of Game Theory, 1974 (Box 46)
  - Japan and Far East Trip, 1954, undated (Box 46)
  - Jet Propulsion Laboratory: Hydrogen Energy Project, 1974-1976, undated (Box 46)
  - Journal of Political Economy, 1938-1939, undated (Box 46)
  - Julius Meinl, 1938, 1975-1976 (Box 46)
  - Kemeny, John G., Game-Theoretic Solution of an Economic Problem, 1956 (Box 47)
  - Kernig, Claus D., 1974-1976 (Box 47)
  - Keynes, John Maynard, 1934-1945, undated (Box 47)
  - Kissinger, Henry A., 1966-1977, undated (Box 47)
  - Kleindorfer, George B., undated (Box 47)
  - Knight, Frank, 1972 (Box 47)
  - Kuhn, Harold, 1971-1972, undated (Box 47)
  - Kyklos Verlag, 1963-1966 (Box 96)
  - Lederberg, Joshua, 1970-1975 (Box 47)
  - Leibnitz, Gottfried Wilhelm von: Papers of, 1949-1953, undated (Box 47)
  - Lexington Books, 1970-1977 (Box 47)
  - L'Huiller, Pierre: Utility Measurement in Situations Involving Risk: A Few Reflect on the Problem by the 'French School', 1958 (Box 47)
  - Liechtenstein, 1967-1968 (Box 96)
  - Liechtenstein, Prince Karl Alfred von, 1971-1975, undated (Box 47)
  - Life Foreign Policy Forum, 1963 (Box 47)
  - Life- Time, 1963-1966 (Box 96)
  - List Gesellschaft (Basel), 1970-1973 (Box 47)
  - List of Rand Reports (Office File), undated (Box 96)
  - Livermore Laboratories, 1965-1968 (Box 96)
  - Lockheed Missiles Systems, 1963-1965 (Box 96)
  - Logic and Economics, 1976 (Box 47)
  - Los, Jerzy, and Maria W., Remarks on the Efficiency Frontiers in von Neumann Models, 1974 (Box 47)
  - Lotteries, 1971-1976 (Box 47)
  - Lucas, William F., 1973-1977 (Box 47)
  - Macroeconomics, 1976, undated (Box 47)
  - Magnification and Business Cycles, undated (Box 47)
  - Malinvaud, Edmond: Programmes d'Expansion et Taux d' Intrt, 1959 (Box 47)
  - Manganese Project, 1956-1957, undated (Box 48)
  - Manganese Project: Financial Statements, 1953-1958 (Box 48)
  - Manganese Project: Reports, 1955-1957 (Box 48)
  - Mann, Fritz Karl, 1960-1970 (Box 48)
  - Marchi, Ezio, 1972-1977, undated (Box 48)
  - Marget, Arthur W.: "Morgenstern on Economic Forecasting, 1929 (Box 48)
  - Marindustrial Research, 1969-1970, undated (Box 48)
  - Marschak, Jacob, 1945 (Box 48)
  - Marx, Communism, etc., 1964-1970 (Box 48)
  - Mathematical Papers Connected with Linear Models, 1948 (Box 96)
  - Maxims of Behavior, 1938-1970, undated (Box 49)
  - Mayer, Dr. Hans, 1950 (Box 49)
  - Meditationes Economicae, 1957-1974, undated (Box 49)
  - Memberships, 1964-1968 (Box 96)
  - Menger, Carl (1840-1921): 1893-1909, 1977 (Box 49)
  - Menger, Karl, 1965-1973 (Box 49)
  - Menges, Gunter, 1973-1977 (Box 49)
  - Military Operations Research: 38th MORS Session, Ft. Eustis, Va., 1976 (Box 49)
  - Misc. Government Agencies, 1964-1967 (Box 96)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Papers, 1960-1976, undated (Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Papers, undated (Box 96)
  - Miscellaneous Notes on Lectures, Classes and Writings, undated (Box 96)
  - Miscellaneous Publishers, 1963-1970 (Box 96)
  - Miscellaneous Universities, 1964-1968 (Box 96)
  - Miscellaneous: On Games Whose Matrices are the Sums of the Matrices of Other Games-MAW, 1949 (Box 96)
  - Modes of Inflation, 1938-1977, undated (Box 49)
  - Modlin Industry Reports, undated (Box 96)
  - Morgenstern, Carl F., 1970s, undated (Box 49)
  - Morgenstern, Karin, undated (Box 49)
  - Morgenstern, Margarete Johanna: Estate, 1949-1969, undated (Box 49)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar: Appointment to Faculty of University of Vienna, 1935 (Box 49)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar: Certificate for Study Completed at Middle School, 1922 (Box 49)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar: Confirmation Certificate, 1917 (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar: Drawings by, 1916, undated (Box 49)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar: Festschrift, 1972-1976, undated (Box 49)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar: Genealogy, 1933 (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar: Grade Reports from School, 1908-1921 (Box 49)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar: Certificate of Dual Austrian and Prussian Citizenship, 1925 (Box 49)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar: Pictures, 1934-1972, undated (Box 49)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar: Projects Agenda, 1975 (Box 49)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar: Seventieth Birth, 1971-1973, undated (Box 49)
  - MRCA, undated (Box 96)
  - MRCA, 1960 (Box 96)
  - MRCA, 1964 (Box 96)
  - MT II ( Draft of Oskar Morgenstern and Gerald L. Thompson's Paper II), undated (Box 96)
  - MT--Consumption Model, 1953-1976, undated (Box 50)
  - Mutual Security Agency, undated (Box 96)
  - Myrdal, Gunnar, 1945, 1962 (Box 50)
  - NASA Shuttle Project, 1970-1971 (Box 96)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1961-1970 (Box 96)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration, 1960s (Box 96)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1936-1951 (Box 50)
  - National Science Foundation, 1970-1976, undated (Box 50)
  - National Science Foundation: Advisory Committee on Research Application Policy, 1973-1976, June 9, 2 folders (Box 50)
  - National Science Foundation: Alpert, Harry Program Director for Socio-Physical Science, 1955-198 (Box 96)
  - National Science Foundation: Advisory Committee on Research Application Policy, 1976, Sept., and undated (Box 51)
  - National Science Foundation: Research and Development Advisory Council, 1973-1977, undated (Box 96)
  - National Space Institute, 1974-1977, undated (Box 96)
  - NATO Conference- Toulon, 1963-1964 (Box 96)
  - NATO Strategy for the Security of the West Conference, 1959 (Box 96)
  - Naval Analysis Group, 1960-1961 (Box 96)
  - Naval Research Logistics Quarterly, 1959-1964 (Box 96)
  - Naval Research Logistics Quarterly, 1965-1969 (Box 96)
  - Naval War College, 1960 (Box 96)
  - NBER-Book, 1959-1962 (Box 96)
  - NBER-Book, 1959-1962 (Box 96)
  - Neumann, John von, 1940-1952, 3 folders (Box 51)
  - Neumann, John von, 1953-1976, 2 folders (Box 52)
  - Neumann, John von: Photographs, 1956, undated (Box 52)
  - Neumann, John von: The Scientific Files of John Von Neumann, 1959: 1959-1960 (Box 52)
  - New Methods of Thought and Procedure- Caltech, 1967-1968 (Box 96)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1976 (Box 52)
  - New York University, 1970-1977, undated, 2 folders (Box 52)
  - New York University: Courses, 1974 (Box 52)
  - New York University: Economic Theory Course, 1974-1975 (Box 52)
  - New York University: Economic Theory Seminar, 1949-1974, undated (Box 52)
  - New York University: Economics of Space Exploration Course, 1972-1976, undated (Box 52)
  - New York University: Game Theory Course, 1969-1975 (Box 52)
  - New York University: History of Economic Thought Course, 1945-1977, undated (Box 52)
  - New York University: Introduction to Political Economy Course, 1973-1975 (Box 53)
  - New York University: Introduction to Political Economy Course, 1974: student Evaluations (Box 53)
  - New York University: Moscowitz Lecture Series, undated (Box 53)
  - New York University: Oskar Morgenstern Research Professorship in Mathematical Economics and Game Theory, 1976-1977, undated (Box 53)
  - New York University: Newspaper Articles, 1970-1988, undated (Box 53)
  - New York University: Non-Lethal Weaponry, 1967 (Box 53)
  - New York University: Notes on Miscellaneous Topics, 1973-1977 (Box 53)
  - New York University: Notes on Various Topics (Fastened into One Group), 1956-1975, undated (Box 53)
  - New York University: Ober Wolfach Conference on Mathematical Economics, 1977 (Box 53)
  - New York University: Office of Emergency Preparedness, 1971-1973 (Box 53)
  - Notes for a Book on Business Cycle, undated (Box 96)
  - NYU Grants and Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 96)
  - Office of Emergency Planning, 1964-1966 (Box 96)
  - Office of Naval Research Progress Report,1949-1956 (Box 96)
  - Office of Naval Research: Economic Conflict and National Security, 1973-1975, undated (Box 54)
  - Office of Naval Research Conference, 1976 (Box 54)
  - Operations Research, 1950-1953 (Box 96)
  - Operations Research Council Washington, D.C., 1966 (Box 96)
  - Organization Theory: Current Notes, 1949-1954, undated (Box 54)
  - Organization Theory: Primary Notes, 1949-1953, undated (Box 54)
  - Osterrichisches Institut Fur Wirtschaftsorschung, 1969 (Box 96)
  - OVP Vienna, 1966 (Box 96)
  - Panel on Arms Limitation and Control, 1959-1960 (Box 97)
  - Paper of Vinod on Input-Output Analsis, undated (Box 97)
  - Papers for Publication on Input-Output Method, 1939 (Box 97)
  - Paris and Brussels Meetings, 1972: 1960-1972, undated (Box 54)
  - Paul D. Converse Awards 1961-1967 (Box 97)
  - Peleg, Bezalel: "A Weakly Maximal Golden-Rule Programme for a Multi-Sector Economy, " 1972 (Box 54)
  - Perroux, Franois, 1974, undated (Box 54)
  - Personnel-Biblography-Personnel Chart, etc., 1961-1962 (Box 97)
  - PHYSICA-VERLAG, 1964-1968 (Box 97)
  - PHYSICA-VERLAG-Game Theory Journal, 1967-1970 (Box 97)
  - Planning, 1942-1945, undated (Box 54)
  - Pirker, Theo, 1972 (Box 54)
  - Poland, 1973-1977, undated (Box 55)
  - Postattack Recover Symposium, 1967 (Box 97)
  - Porsche, Ferdinand, 1972-1977 (Box 55)
  - Power, 1972-1975, undated (Box 55)
  - Power and Game Theory, 1954-1972, undated, 2 folders (Box 55)
  - Predictions, undated (Box 97)
  - President's Science Advisory Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 97)
  - Price Theory Bibliography, 1951, undated (Box 55)
  - Princeton High Schools, 1965 (Box 97)
  - Princeton Logisics Research Project (under A.W. Tucker), undated (Box 97)
  - Princeton University Conference, 1960 (Box 97)
  - Princeton University Conference, 1963 (Box 97)
  - Princeton University Conference, 1969 (Box 97)
  - Princeton University Conference Aerospace Methods, 1969 (Box 97)
  - Princeton University Press, 1963-1970 (Box 97)
  - Princeton University: 1948-1977 (Box 55)
  - Princeton University: Abolition of Graduate Undergraduate Division, 1969-1970 (Box 55)
  - Princeton University: Business Cycles Course, 1961 (Box 55)
  - Princeton University: Department of Economics and Social Institutions, 1941-1947 (Box 55)
  - Princeton University: Department of Economics and Social Institutions, 1948-1967, undated, 3 folders (Box 56)
  - Princeton University: Econometric Research Program, 1969 (Box 56)
  - Princeton University: Economic Theory Graduate Course, 1938-1957 (Box 56)
  - Princeton University: Economics 313 (Theory), 1950-1957 (Box 56)
  - Princeton University: History of Economic Thought Course, 1944-1967 (Box 56)
  - Princeton University: Introduction to Political Economy (Course), 1955-1975 (Box 56)
  - Princeton University: Personnel, 1953-1954 (Box 56)
  - Princeton University: Public Lectures, 1949 (Box 56)
  - Princeton University: Research Contract Correspondence and Documents (especially Office of Naval Research), 1946-1955, undated (Box 56)
  - Princeton University: Research Contract Financial Statements, 1950-1964, undated, 2 folders (Box 57)
  - Princeton University: Research Contract Ledger Accounts, 1959-1963, 2 folders (Box 57)
  - Princeton University: Research Projects, 1953-1956, undated (Box 57)
  - Princeton University: Student Theses, 1953-1954, undated (Box 57)
  - Princeton University Press, 1941-1976, undated (Box 57)
  - Principles of Economic Liberalism, 1939 (Box 57)
  - Producers Cost Function Studies, undated (Box 97)
  - Prognos (European Center for Applied Economic Research), 1962-1977, undated, 7 folders (Box 58)
  - Project Staff Princeton Econometric Studies No.2, 1950 (Box 97)
  - Project Budget Reports, 1970-1975 (Box 58)
  - Project Matters Consultants Agreements 1956-1958 (Box 97)
  - Project Matters: Personnel Academic, 1956-1958 (Box 97)
  - Project Matters: Personnel Non-Academic, 1956-1958 (Box 97)
  - Question of National Defense, undated (Box 97)
  - Question of National Defense, 1959 (Box 59)
  - RAMIS, 1971-1978, undated (Box 59)
  - RAND Corporation, 1948-1950 (Box 97)
  - RAND Corporation 1954-1958 (Box 97)
  - Rand Corporation, 1948-1975, undated, 2 folders (Box 59)
  - Rand Corporation Trip, 1952 (Box 59)
  - Random House, 1958 (Box 97)
  - RCA Consulting, 1963-1966 (Box 97)
  - RCAF Staff College Journal, 1959-1960 (Box 97)
  - Reinhardt, U., "Lockheed's Tri-Star: An Application of Capital-Budgeting Techinques," 1972 (Box 59)
  - Report of Executive Committee (Nat'l Security Resources Board), 1949 (Box 97)
  - Requests for Papers, 1963-1969 (Box 97)
  - Review of: "the Question of National Defense", undated (Box 97)
  - Review, Book, 1953-1958 (Box 97)
  - Risk, 1934-1943, undated (Box 59)
  - Rockefeller, John D., III, 1938 (Box 59)
  - Rockefeller Bros., 1973-1976, undated (Box 59)
  - Rockefeller University: Conference on "Beyond Tomorrow, Trends, and Prospects in Medical Science, 1976 (Box 59)
  - Rdding, Walburga, 1973-1977, undated (Box 59)
  - Rueff, Jacques, 1961-1970, undated (Box 59)
  - Rueff, Jacques, and Institut de France, 1970-1977 (Box 59)
  - Russian Research, 1953-1955 (Box 97)
  - Rutgers University: Symposium on Methodology in Finance-Investments, 1969-1971, n.d (Box 60)
  - Salaries Material, 1952-1958 (Box 98)
  - Salin, Edgar, 1972-1975 (Box 60)
  - Samuelson, Paul, 1950, 1969 (Box 60)
  - Sandia Corporation, 1956-1958 (Box 98)
  - Scandinavia, 1972-1977, undated (Box 60)
  - Schlesinger, Karl, 1966-1968, undated (Box 60)
  - Scholars' Curriculum Vitae: R. Reichardt and Antares Parvulescu (Box 60)
  - Schumpeter, Joseph A., 1950-1951, undated (Box 60)
  - Scientific Associates, 1964-1974, undated (Box 60)
  - Second International Workshop in Game Theory, University of Cal., Berkeley, 1970 (Box 98)
  - Secretary of the Navy, 1957-1959 (Box 98)
  - Security Clearance, 1967-1977, undated (Box 60)
  - Semi-Philosophical Varia, 1955-1973, undated (Box 60)
  - Shephard, Ronald W., 1970-1977 (Box 60)
  - Shubik, Martin, 1960-1972, June, 2 folders (Box 60)
  - Shubik, Martin, 1973-1977, undated, 2 folders (Box 61)
  - Simplex Method, undated (Box 98)
  - Social Sciences and Economics in Europe, 1938 (Box 61)
  - Socit de Recherche Operationnelle et d'conomie Applique S.A., 1971-1972, undated (Box 61)
  - Solidarity of Money Markets, 1944 (Box 98)
  - Somary, Wolfgang F., 1968-1972 (Box 61)
  - Space Ventues, Inc., 1962-1963 (Box 99)
  - Some Econometric Relationships Bearing Upon the Theory of Interest, by Charles F. Roos and Wendell P. Ayres, 1941 (Box 61)
  - Space, 1968-1976, undated (Box 61)
  - Space Conference, 1976-1977 (Box 61)
  - Spieltheorie und Wirtschafts Theorie, 1948; 1963 (Box 61)
  - Springer Verlag, 1974-1977 (Box 61)
  - Stagnation, 1939-1954, undated (Box 61)
  - Sthl, Ingolf, 1972-1973 (Box 61)
  - Statistical Error, circa 1950s (Box 61)
  - Stock Market, 1961-1964 (Box 99)
  - Stock Market Problems, 1970-1975, 1987 (Box 61)
  - Stock Markets and International Cycles, 1941-1946, undated (Box 62)
  - Studies in Game Theory, 1975 (Box 62)
  - Studies in International Conflict and Integration, 1963-1966 (Box 99)
  - Subjective Probability, 1966 (Box 62)
  - Symposium on Methodology, Bethesda, 1973: 1971-1973, undated (Box 62)
  - Syracuse University ,March, 1964 (Box 99)
  - Technische Universitat Berlin, 1964-1966 (Box 99)
  - Technische Universitt Berlin, 1963-1964 (Box 62)
  - Technology, 1962 (Box 99)
  - Technology Transfer, 1973-1975, undated (Box 62)
  - Texas A and M, 1967-1968 (Box 99)
  - Texas Agricultural and Mechanical University, 1970-1975, undated (Box 62)
  - Theory of Organization: Bibliography (Box 62)
  - Thompson, Gerald L., 1960-1976, n.d (Box 62)
  - Thompson, Gerald L.: The von Neumann Model, 1956-1975, undated, 2 folders (Box 62)
  - Thorp, Edward O., 1971-1974, undated (Box 62)
  - Time Structure of Consumption, 1970 (Box 62)
  - Tomlin, S. G., 1968-1972 (Box 62)
  - Topics in Applied Economic Theory, Proposed Research Project To Be Funded by Exxon, 1976 (Box 62)
  - Topics in Applied Economic Theory, Proposed Research Project To Be Funded by Exxon, 1977, undated (Box 63)
  - Trnquist, Leo, 1945-1969 (Box 63)
  - Transformation of Knowledge, 1970-1973 (Box 63)
  - Treichl, Heinrich, 1973-1977 (Box 63)
  - Trilateral Commission, 1975-1976, undated (Box 63)
  - Trip to Honolulu, Hawaii, 1962 (Box 99)
  - Trips, Conferences, Speaking Engagements, 1951-1953 (Box 63)
  - 21x21 Matrices, undated (Box 99)
  - United States. Department of the Navy. General Board, 1948 (Box 63)
  - United States Strategic Bombing Survey, 1945-1947 (Box 63)
  - University Matters: Departmental 1960-1962 (Box 99)
  - University Matters: General, 1959-1962 (Box 99)
  - University of Basel, 1960 (Box 63)
  - University of California, San Diego December 16, 1969-1970 (Box 99)
  - University of Georgia: Lectures, 1949 (Box 63)
  - University of Michigan Summer Seminar on Design of Experiments on Decision Proccesses, 1952-1962 (Box 99)
  - University of Pennsylvania: American Civilization Advisory Council, 1974-1977, undated (Box 63)
  - University of Vienna, 1964-1966 (Box 99)
  - University of Vienna: Seminars, 1930-1933, undated (Box 63)
  - University of Vienna: 600th Anniversary, 1965: 1964-1966, undated (Includes photographs of Morgenstern, etc.) (Box 63)
  - University Policies and Procedures, 1952 (Box 99)
  - Uranium, 1957 (Box 99)
  - Utilities: Axiomatic, 1944-1946, undated (Box 63)
  - Utility Theory (Allais), 1967-1977, undated (Box 63)
  - Utility Theory (Gambling, etc.), 1944-1971, undated (Box 63)
  - Utility Theory: Rational Decisions under Risk, Allais and Hagen, eds., 1973-1974 (Box 63)
  - Vienna Conference Institute for Advanced Study, 1969-1970 (Box 99)
  - Vienna Conference, 1972, undated (Box 64)
  - Vienna-Poland Trip, 1972: 1972-1974, undated (Box 64)
  - Vietnam, 1967 (Box 64)
  - Viner, Jacob, 1957-1970 (Box 64)
  - Viti de Marco, Antonio de, and Family, 1929-1970 (Box 64)
  - Vollkommene Voraussicht und Wirtschaftliches Gleichgewicht, 1934-1935 (Box 64)
  - Vorbereitende Notizen, 1934-1936, undated (Box 64)
  - Vorob'ev, N. N., 1967-1976, undated (Box 64)
  - Wald, Abraham, 1938-1975 (includes photographs) (Box 64)
  - Washington Trip, 1970: 1970-1973, undated (Box 64)
  - Washington Trip, 1973 (Box 64)
  - Water Issues, 1963-1965 (Box 64)
  - Weil, Roman L., Jr., 1968-1970 (Box 64)
  - Welfare Economics, 1953 (Box 65)
  - Westwood Research, 1970 (Box 65)
  - Weyl, Hermann, 1953-1973 (Box 65)
  - Whig- Cliosophic Society, 1966 (Box 99)
  - White House Matters, 1969-1970 (Box 99)
  - Whitin, Thomson, M., 1971-1974 (Box 65)
  - Weisner, Maurice, F., 1973-1976 (Box 65)
  - Wiley-Interscience, 1974-1975 (Box 65)
  - Wissensoziologische Varia, 1927-1930 (Box 65)
  - Witherspoon, Welthandel, and Other Lectures, 1963-1966 (Box 65)
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, 1973-1975, undated (Box 65)
  - Woodrow Wilson School Policy Research Conference, 1965 (Box 99)
  - Work Sheets Estimation of Omitted Trade Margins, 1939 (Box 99)
  - Yale University Graduate Club Nov. 20 ,1969-1970 (Box 99)
  - York, Herbert F., 1973 (Box 65)
  - Zeit, Gleichgewicht und Kontinuum, 1933 (Box 65)
  - Zeit und Preise, 1930-1933 (Box 65)
  - Zeitschrift Fuer Nationaloekonomie, 1958 (Box 99)
- Mathematica Materials, 1958-1977, 3 boxes
  This part of the collection comprises of documents related to Morgenstern's activities with Mathematica, a consulting company that Morgenstern co-founded in 1962. Documents include correspondence, memos, policy reports, project proposals, and research papers. The institutions that are often mentioned include NASA, Office of Naval Research, and Sandia Corporation. Topics, among others, relate to analysis of military conflicts, economics of the space program, management research, or peaceful use of nuclear energy. Some materials related to Mathematica Series are still scattered across the rest of the collection.
  - American Metal Climax, Inc., 1971-1975, undated (Box 91)
  - Analysis Support Center and Craig C. Sherbrooke, 1973-1977 (Box 91)
  - Analytical Support Center (Support to U.S. Intelligence Community in Policy Analysis), 1973-1975, 3 folders (Box 91)
  - Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, 1963-1976, undated, 3 folders (Box 91)
  - Army Material Command, 1967 (Box 91)
  - Atomic Energy Commission, 1963-1973, undated (Box 91)
  - Austria, 1971-1974 (Box 91)
  - Central Intelligence Agency, 1971-1976, undated (Box 91)
  - Chief of Naval Operations, 1969-1970 (Box 91)
  - Chrysler and Porsche, 1975-1977, undated (Box 91)
  - CIBA, Ltd. (Basel), 1969-1970 (Box 91)
  - Computer Assisted Performance Analysis, 1968 Jul. (Box 91)
  - Control of Investment and Modern Technology (unpublished manuscript), 1968, 1970 (Box 91)
  - Cotter Donald R., Malcolm R. Currie, and National Interests, 1967-1976, undated (Box 91)
  - Department of Navy, 1966 (Box 91)
  - European Expansion, 1969 (Box 91)
  - Forecasting Future Development - Report, 1969 Apr. (Box 91)
  - Mathematica: Projects, 1970-1977 (Box 91)
  - Measuring the Performance of Security Analysts, 1969 (Box 91)